yoono.com 2014-04-03

# Privacy - Yoono

##  Privacy Policy - Last Modified on May 1, 2009 

Click here to see previous version

This Privacy Policy explains what information of yours will be collected by Yoono, Inc. ("Yoono," "we," or "us") when you use Yoono.com and related services (the "Service"), how the information will be used, and how you can control the collection, correction and/or deletion of information. We will not use or share your personally identifiable information with anyone except as described in this Privacy Policy. As used in this Privacy Policy, "personally identifiable information" means information that identifies or can be used to identify or contact you, including your name, email address, postal address, and phone number, but not including your IP address (except in combination with one or more of the above). 

Overview 

Yoono sincerely desires to be transparent with users with regard to privacy when using the Service. We've tried to write this document in plain language as much as possible in order to facilitate ease of understanding. We don't do anything with your information other than as described in this Privacy Policy and as laid out in the Yoono Terms of Use Agreement. For full details, please read the full Privacy Policy below as well as our Terms of Use Agreement. 

Information Collection and Use 

**Registration Information**  
When you register with Yoono, you choose a username for Yoono and provide us with your email address. 

**Login Information for 3rd Party Services**  
Yoono's Service allows you to connect to third-party services such as Facebook, MySpace, Twitter, AIM and more. These services vary in the way they allow third parties such as Yoono to connect to them. In all cases, Yoono seeks to provide the user the most private solution possible and to store both your username and password only where necessary to give you seamless access to a particular service from Yoono. For example, Facebook offers an authentication solution for Yoono whereby you login on a Facebook web page and receive an authorization token from Facebook for Yoono but do not provide your Facebook login information directly to Yoono. Other services such as Twitter and many instant messaging services currently do not provide similar solutions.  
For services that do not have an authentication solution for Yoono that avoids the need for storage of login information by us, Yoono takes the following approach: 

  1. We store the username provided by you to Yoono on our servers.
  2. Whenever possible, we enable the password manager in your web browser, or similar local storage solution, to store your password for the service in lieu of storing it on our servers.
  3. When not possible to store passwords client side (i.e. in your browser), we store on Yoono's servers and encrypt your password - currently this is the case for instant messaging services (AIM, MSN Live Messenger, Yahoo! Messenger, and Google Talk) only.

We store your username (and password as indicated above) on our servers solely for the purpose of allowing you to automatically sign in to your services when you launch Yoono. 

**Use of Cookies**  
When you download and use the Yoono Sidebar, we may send one or more cookies - a small text file containing a string of alphanumeric characters - to your computer that uniquely identifies your web browser and lets Yoono help you log in automatically to the Service. A cookie does not collect personally identifiable information about you.  
Yoono uses both session cookies and persistent cookies. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive after you close your browser. Persistent cookies may be used by your browser on subsequent visits to the site. Persistent cookies can be removed by following your web browser's directions for cookie deletion. A session cookie is temporary and disappears after you close your browser. You can reset your web browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent, however some features of the Service may not function properly if the ability to accept cookies is disabled. 

**General Log File Information**  
Log file information is information automatically reported by your browser each time you access a web page. When you use the Yoono Sidebar, our servers automatically record certain information that your web browser sends whenever you visit a website (note that secure websites (https) are excluded - no data is sent when on a secure site). This data is aggregated and anonymized - it never contains personally identifiable information.   
This data is used to improve the Yoono service, our recommendations, and help resolve problems with our software. Server logs may include information such as the web page visited, your Internet Protocol ("IP") address, browser type, referring/exit pages and URLs, number of clicks, domain names, landing pages, pages viewed, keywords and other similar information. 

**Bookmark Sync**  
If you choose to use Yoono's bookmark synchronization feature, we will store your bookmarks on our server in order to enable synchronization across your computers. We additionally use anonymous, aggregated bookmark information to improve our related websites recommendations. 

**How we Use Your Information**  
In addition to as described above, we use cookies, bookmarks and log file information to: (a) remember information so that you will not have to re-enter it during your visit or the next time you visit the site/Service; (b) provide custom, personalized content and information; (c) monitor the effectiveness of our service; (d) monitor aggregate metrics such as total number of visitors and traffic; (e) and diagnose or fix technology problems reported by our users. 

**Discovery Feature**  
Yoono's Discovery feature is designed to show you content (websites, videos, images, etc.) related to the website you are currently viewing. In order to do this, Yoono: 

  1. Extracts keywords from the page you are viewing and sends those keywords to our servers and third party sites such as Google to determine the best recommendations to show you, however Yoono never sends personally identifiable information about you when sending these keywords to our servers or those of third parties to show you related information
  2. In order to show you related websites, the URL of the page you are viewing is sent to Yoono's servers, however note that Yoono does not send personally identifiable information about you when sending these URLs to our servers and does not send these URLs to any third parties (Note: if the website you are using is poorly coded and includes your personally identifiable information within its URLs, this information can be unintentionally sent to our servers)
  3. Keywords extracted and URLs sent to our servers are only stored on our servers in an anonymized and aggregated fashion - they never contain personally identifiable information

**Shared Content**  
Any content that you voluntarily disclose for posting to the Service (for instance, shared images, videos, etc.) becomes available to the public, unless you activate the proper privacy options. If you remove your User Content (as defined in the Terms of Use Agreement), copies may remain viewable in cached and archived pages or if other users have copied or stored your User Content.  
Yoono reserves the right, but has no obligation, to monitor the User Content you post on the site. Yoono has the right to remove any such information or material for any reason or no reason, including without limitation, if in its sole opinion, such information or material violates, or may violate, any applicable law or our Terms of Use Agreement or to protect or defend its rights or property or those of any third party. Yoono also reserves the right to remove information upon the request of any third party. 

**Email**  
By providing Yoono your email address you consent to our using the email address to send you Service-related notices, including any notices required by law, in lieu of communication by postal mail, except as otherwise required by mandatory provisions of applicable law that cannot be contractually derogated from. We may also use your email address to send you other messages, such as newsletters or changes to features of the Service. If you do not want to receive such email messages, you may opt out by taking the unsubscribe steps outlined in the email itself. Opting out may prevent you from receiving email messages regarding updates or improvements.  
If you correspond with us by email, we may retain the content of your email messages, your email address and our responses. This information is used solely for your account record and not shared with any third parties.  
When you provide another person's email address to invite that person to use Yoono or to find a contact on Yoono, we use that person's email address solely for your intended purpose and do not otherwise save or use that person's email address. 

How We Share Your Information 

Yoono may use certain information about you and/or your User Content without identifying you as an individual to third parties. We do this for purposes such as analyzing how the Service is used, diagnosing service or technical problems, maintaining security, and personalizing content. 

**Personally Identifiable Information:**  
Yoono will not rent or sell your personally identifiable information to others and will not share it with others except as provided herein. We engage certain trusted third parties to perform functions and provide services to us, including, without limitation, data hosting, storage and maintenance. We will share your personally identifiable information with these third parties, but only to the extent necessary to perform these functions and provide such services, and only pursuant to binding contractual obligations requiring such third parties to maintain the privacy and security of your data. If you invite a friend to join Yoono, your email address and name are used and disclosed to the user you are inviting. 

As we develop our business, we may buy or sell assets or business offerings - for example if Yoono or part of the Yoono service is acquired by a third party. Customer, email, and visitor information is generally one of the transferred business assets in these types of transactions. We may also transfer such information in the course of corporate divestitures, mergers, or dissolution. 

Except as otherwise described in this privacy statement, Yoono will not disclose personally identifiable information to any third party unless required to do so by law or subpoena or if we believe that such action is necessary to (a) conform to the law, comply with legal process served on us or our affiliates, or investigate, prevent, or take action regarding suspected or actual illegal activities; (b) to enforce our Terms of Use, take precautions against liability, to investigate and defend ourselves against any third-party claims or allegations, to assist government enforcement agencies, or to protect the security or integrity of our site; and (c) to exercise or protect the rights, property, or personal safety of Yoono, our users or others. 

**Non-Personally Identifiable Information:**  
We may share non-personally identifiable information (such as extracted keyword data) with third parties services in order to increase the relevance of the Discovery recommendations, shopping recommendations, and advertisements we display. Yoono allows other companies, called third-party ad servers or ad networks, to serve advertisements on the Yoono site and sidebar. These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to send, directly to your browser, the advertisements and links that appear on Yoono. They may automatically retrieve your IP address when this happens. They may also use other technologies (such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons) to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and to personalize the advertising content. 

Yoono does not provide any personally identifiable information to these third-party ad servers or ad networks without your consent. 

You should additionally consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers or ad networks (and other services linked to Yoono, like Facebook, Twitter, AIM etc.). Yoono's Privacy Policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such advertisers and third party services. 

How We Protect Your Information 

Yoono uses commercially reasonable physical, managerial, and technical safeguards to preserve the integrity and security of your personally identifiable information. We cannot, however, ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to Yoono and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission of information, Yoono makes commercially reasonable efforts to ensure the security of our systems. However, please note that this is not a guarantee that such information may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by breach of any of our physical, technical, or managerial safeguards. 

To protect your privacy and security, we take reasonable steps (such as requesting a unique password) to verify your identity before granting you access to your account. You are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your unique password and account information, and for controlling access to your email communications from Yoono, at all times. 

**Management of Your Information**  
You may, of course, decline to submit personally identifiable information through Yoono, in which case Yoono may not be able to provide certain services to you. You can review and correct the information about you that Yoono keeps on file by contacting us directly at [privacy@yoono.com](mailto:privacy@yoono.com). 

The collection, use, and sharing of information contemplated in this Privacy Policy involves a transfer of the information to the United States and possibly other jurisdictions that may not have equivalent laws and rules regarding personally identifiable information as your country of residency. 

**Children's Privacy**  
Yoono does not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from anyone under the age of 13 or knowingly allow such persons to register. If you are under 13, please do not send any information about yourself to us, including your name, address, telephone number, or email address. No one under age 13 is allowed to provide any personal information to or on Yoono. In the event that we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under age 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us at [privacy@yoono.com](mailto:privacy@yoono.com). 

**Links to Other Web Sites**  
We are not responsible for the practices employed by Web sites linked to or from our Service nor the information or content contained therein. Please remember that when you use a link to go from our Service site to another Web site (or to use another service or website from our service), our Privacy Policy does not apply to that site or service. Your browsing and interaction on any other Web site, including those that have a link on our Web site or Service, is subject to that Web site's own rules and policies. Please read over those rules and policies before proceeding. 

**Notification Procedures**  
It is our policy to provide notifications, whether such notifications are required by law or are for marketing or other business related purposes, to you via email notice, written or hard copy notice, or through conspicuous posting of such notice on our Service, as determined by Yoono in its sole discretion. We reserve the right to determine the form and means of providing notifications to you, provided that you may opt out of certain means of notification as described in this Privacy Policy. 

**Changes to Our Privacy Policy**  
If we change our privacy policies and procedures, we will post those changes on our website to keep you aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances we may disclose it. Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page. 

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, please contact us at [privacy@yoono.com](mailto:privacy@yoono.com), or send mail to: 

> **Yoono, Inc.**  
>  **300 De Haro St, South Train**  
>  **San Francisco CA 94103**  
>
